This is some of the world's purest
water, and I'm about [music] to drink
it. Hold on. Don't drink water in random
places. The scientist with us tested
this and said that it was okay. These
rivers only exist for a few weeks during
the Antarctic summers when the sun never
sets. This water comes from melting
glaciers, [music] meaning it's been
trapped in the ice for hundreds or
thousands of years. So, does that mean
there could be ancient bacteria in it?
Unlikely, because when the ice forms, it
acts like a natural filter forcing out
dust and salt and pollutants. And all
that pressure forces out all sorts of
gases and air bubbles, too. So, when it
melts, it looks crystal clear. [music]
So, what makes the rivers blue? That
color comes from the ice underneath.
That ice is super compact and dense,
[music] so it absorbs red and yellow
light reflecting back bright blue.
That's really genuinely delicious. For
more optimistic science and tech
stories, subscribe.